Preliminary Guide to the Cornelius Osgood Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Cornelius Osgood papers
1927-1983
MS 1366
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
7.5
(15 boxes)
The papers consist of chapter drafts of Fallen Leaves written by Cornelius Osgood. The additional material consist of photographs taken by Cornelius Osgood during his career as an ethnologist.
Osgood, Cornelius, 1905-1985
Conditions Governing Access
The papers are closed during the lifetime of Sui-ling Osgood or until January 1, 2022 whichever occurs first.
Biographical / Historical
Cornelius Osgood was born in Winchester, Massachusetts, on March 20, 1905. He attended the University of Chicago, attaining the degree of Ph.B. in 1927 and Ph.D. in 1930. He married Harriett Ellen Keeney on September 25, 1930. The couple had two daughters before Harriett's death in 1962. On December 23, 1963, Osgood remarried, to Soo Sui-ling. Osgood was an ethnologist who worked as curator at various museums throughout the country, including the Yale Peabody Museum. He also authored several books about East Asia. Cornelius Osgood died on January 6, 1985.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged by the original inventory and additional material.
Custodial History
Gift of Cornelius Osgood, 1983. Gift of Sui-Ling Osgood, 2011.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of chapter drafts of Fallen Leaves written by Cornelius Osgood. The additional material consists of photographs taken by Cornelius Osgood during his career as an ethnologist.
Osgood, Cornelius, 1905-1985
- Fallen Leaves drafts, 1983-04-1983-06
  - Chapters 1A-41 (958p. + 55p.), 1983 April (Box 1)
  - Chapters 42-91 (1199p.), 1983 April (Box 2)
  - Chapters 92-140 (1050p.), 1983 June (Box 3)
  - Chapters 141-172 (1063p.), 1983 June (Box 4)
  - Chapters 173-218 (1066p.), 1983 June (Box 5)
  - Chapters 219-270 (1059p.), 1983 June (Box 6)
  - Chapters 271-315 (1046p.), 1983 June (Box 7)
  - Chapters 316-354 (1036p.), 1983 June (Box 8)
- Additional Material, 1927-1966; Accession 2012-M-026
  Arrangement
  The addition to the Cornelius Osgood papers is arranged alphabetically by location.
  Scope and Contents
  The addition consists of photographs taken by Cornelius Osgood during his career as an ethnologist from 1927 to 1966. The photographs document the lives of people, commercial and agricultural enterprises, street scenes, archaelogical excavations, and cultural events in Asia, the Americas and the Caribbean.
  - Alaska
    - Alaska Expedition - Tanaina, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alaska - General, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Anvik, 1934, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Holy Cross, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Ingalik Indians, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Ingalik Masks, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ingalik Specimens (Chapman's at Anvik), Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Marshall, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Pearce R. Expedition, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Valdez - Fairbanks Trail, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - China, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cuba, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Florida Expedition, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hong Kong
    - Ap Lei Chau Island
      The photographs of Ap Lei Chau Island document people, cultural events, agriculture, manufacturing of kegs, paper, ink and soy sauce and street scenes in the districts of Nam Sa Wan, Shah Sheh Wan, and Pian Sheh Wan.
      - 1960-1966 (Box 2)
      - 1960-1966 (Box 3)
      - 1960-1966 (Box 4)
      - 1960-1966 (Box 5)
  - Kanghwa - Korea, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 1-8)
  - Northwest Territory - Canada, 1927-1929 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Panama - Chiriqui, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - South America
    - General, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Venezuela, 1926-1941 (Box 7, Folder 3-5)
  - Trinidad, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 6-7)